Now listen, yo!
People put your guns up
First I'll run dat
Run around and shoot them
Brand new sound, yes still survival
Here comes the sound boy, live in this world
Intelligence, strength, and luck are swirling, flow
My swelled mind is candid
One punch to Banner in Savannah
An easy knockout, bam bam bam
One time for your mind, live through this
Around the world
It haunts me, the pain of the past
Around the noble god are borrowed things
When the seed that's sown flowers, whose is it
Live and fire the arrow of faith, more more more
There is no peace where you're going
Come on, stand up, don't give up the fight
Now, yes, this instant, die die die
Big shooter, living fast, blazing
Beat you up, cut it open, break
Shot shooter, he lived fast, crazy
Adjust your sights at point-blank range, break
Big shooter, living fast, blazing
Beat you up, cut it open, break
Shot shooter, he lived fast, crazy
Adjust your sights at point-blank range, break
（古田(ふるた)）ちょっと待て！
（梶浦(かじうら)）ああ？
Wait!
Huh?
君たちは 一体 何をやってるんだ？
What on Earth do you two think you're doing?!
Like I said, we're trying to
get rid of the Kurono Alien.
（梶浦）
だから 玄野(くろの)星人退治ですよ
But she's got nothing to do with it!
彼女は関係ないだろう　やめなさい
Stop this!
（計(けい)）あっ…
Why don't you tell that to Kurono?
それは玄野に言ってくださいよ
Things turned out this way because
he's putting up a fight.
ヤツが抵抗するから
こういうことになったんでね
But...
（古田）しかし…
（計）あっ…
Kishimoto!
（古田）またか
（佳乃(よしの)）幻覚？
Is it happening again?
The hallucinations?
Kurono, what do you see?
（佳乃）玄野君 何が見えるの？
（計）あっ！
（岸本）玄野君 もうダメだよ
助からないって
Kurono... It's too late.
You won't make it.
Gantz! Do this all you want, but it
won't work! I won't be fooled!
ガンツ 何度やっても同じだ
俺はダマされない
死ぬしかないんだよ
The only thing you can do is die.
I won't die! I won't!
俺は死なない 絶対に！
I wanted to live.
（岸本）私 生きたかったよ
No Labyrinth is Inescapable
Why are you the only one still alive,
Kurono? It's not fair!
（岸本）
どうして玄野君だけ生きてるの？
ズルイよ そんなの
Stop it!
やめろー！
I didn't want to die... That's the truth!
（岸本）死にたくなかった
ホントだよ
死にたくなかったんだよ
I never wanted to die!
You're the only one who survived.
Kato, Sei and everyone else...
玄野君だけ生き残って
加藤(かとう)君も聖(せい)さんも みんな…
Why were you the only one saved?
どうして玄野君だけ…
（計）違う 違う 違う！
It's not true! It's not true! It's not true!
Why were you the only one saved?
（みか）私も違うと思うわ！
I don't think it's true either!
（岸本）
玄野君は もしかしたら―
I think that maybe Kurono has lost
the people he cares about.
大切な人たちを
失ったんじゃないかと思う
そうじゃなきゃ
人前で泣いたりしないと思うの
Otherwise he wouldn't cry in front others!
（梶浦）黙れよ 黙れ！
（みか）ウッ！
Shut up! Shut the hell up!
Ma... Maybe everything he told us was true!
（みか）
だったら 彼の言ってることは―
全部ホントなんじゃないの？
Maybe it's Gantz and these two
that are the bad guys!
悪いのはガンツで…
この人たちで…
彼は悪くないんじゃないの？
（梶浦）てめえ 殺すぞ！
I don't think it's Kurono at all!
I'll fuckin' kill ya!
Go ahead and kill me!
（みか・岸本）
殺すなら殺しなさいよ！
Go ahead and kill me!
I've already died once, so who cares?!
どうせ １回死んでるんだから
どうってことないわ
I've already died once, so who cares?!
I've already died once, so who cares?! Kill me!
Kill me!
殺しなさいよ！
（みか・岸本）あなたたち
さっきから いろいろ言ってるけど
You two have been telling us all these things,
彼を殺したいだけなんじゃないの？
違うの？
but I think the truth is, you just want
to kill Kurono! Am I wrong?!
You said it's to survive, but you
just want to kill Kurono...
（岸本）ホントは助かりたいとか
そういうんじゃなくて―
ただ玄野君を…
人を殺したいだけなんじゃないの？
You just want to kill SOMEBODY!
Isn't that right?!
Kishimoto...
（計）岸本…
（岸本）玄野君
Kurono.
Let's go back together, okay?
一緒に帰ろうよ ねっ？
Let's all go back together!
（加藤）みんなで一緒に帰ろう
You bitch!
（梶浦）このー！
（みか）アアッ！
（梶浦）オラッ！
オラッ！ オラッ！
（みかの悲鳴）
（室戸(むろと)）
チッ… バ～カ　キレんなよ
Dumbass. Don't go losing it now.
Kishimoto!
（計）岸本…
Hey, you!
（古田）お… おい 君
（ぶつかる音）
（梶浦）ウワッ…
く… 玄野！
Kurono!
Hajime!
（梶浦）
一(はじめ)！ 外に出たぞ 逃がすな！
He took off! Don't let him get away!
C'mon, go after him!
おい 早く追っかけろ！
（室戸）わ… 分かりましたよ
O... Okay.
Hey! Wait!
おい 待て… うん？
It's not true, is it?
（みか）違うんでしょう？ 君
Hey!
（みか）ねえ
（計）えっ？
You... You're not an alien, are you?
君 玄野星人なんかじゃ
ないんでしょう？
Of course not!
当たり前だろう！
Let's go!
（梶浦）行くぞ
Wait!
（古田）待て
（梶浦・室戸）ああ？
Did you really kill some homeless people?
本当にホームレスを殺したのか？
Oh, shut up. We can talk about that later.
うるせえな　そんなの あと あと
Don't do it! Put the gun down!
（古田）やめろ！ 銃を下ろせ
Pops, these guys have a sick look in their eyes.
（野崎(のざき)）
おっさん こいつら 目つきが危ない
Look, just put it down!
（古田）いいから 下ろせ！
Jeez! What a pain in the ass!
なんだ？ うぜえな
Answer the question!
答えろ　あんたらは
本当にホームレスを殺したのか？
Did you really kill some homeless people?
（みか）アアッ… 待って
Hold on.
What is it?
何だよ？
（みか）落としてきちゃった
I dropped it.
ああ？ 何を？
Huh? Dropped what?
The book. I want to go back and get it.
本 取りに戻りたいんだけど…
Just forget about that.
（計）放っとけよ そんな物(もん)
（みか）大事な本なの
But it's important.
There's a wonderful line on the first page.
最初のページに
とっても いいことが書いてあって
And I... I just want to read the rest of the book!
私 どうしても続きが読みたいの
What the hell are you talking about?
何言ってんだよ？
"No labyrinth is inescapable."
（みか）“出られない迷宮はない”
（計）えっ？
That's what it says on the first page.
最初のページに そう書いてあるの
ミランダ・フォスターの
「迷宮」っていう本なの
It's a book called "Labyrinth"
by Miranda Foster.
Answer the question!
（古田）どうなんだ？
So what if we did?
だったら どうだってんだよ？
They have no jobs, they get drunk
in the middle of the afternoon...
働きもしねえで昼間っから
コップ酒食らってるゴミどもだぞ
They're nothing but garbage!
Who cares if they die or not?
死んだって関係ねえだろう
Did you do it, too?
（古田）君も やったのか？
I, I...
ぼ… 僕は…
（佳乃）どうなの？
Well?!
Yes, he did.
やってるさ
（斉藤(さいとう)）えっ？
His eyes say so.
そういう目だ
I... I had no choice!
し… しかたなかったんですよ
僕は殺すつもりはなかった
I didn't mean to kill them!
Huh? What the hell are you talking about?
ああ？ 何言ってんだ？ てめえ
I told him I don't want to!
僕は
いつもイヤだって言ってたんです
でも でも…
But, but Mr. Kajiura always
forced me to go with him, and...
梶浦さんに無理やり
ついてこいって言われて…
I really didn't mean to.
（室戸）ホントに
わざとじゃなかったんです
（室戸）梶浦さんが
あんまり暴れるもんだから―
One time Mr. Kajiura went too far,
ホームレスの人たちに
囲まれちゃって…
and before we knew it we were
surrounded by homeless people.
They were the ones who attacked US
with metal baseball bats!
金属バットで殴りかかってきたのは
あの人たちのほうなんです
Hajime! Cut the bullshit already!
はじめ！
てめえ 寝言こいてんじゃねえぞ！
この殺人オタクがよ！
（室戸）違うんです
You're a sick murderer!
That's not true!
I got scared and tried to run away,
so I just swung the bat left and right.
怖くなって逃げようとして 夢中で
バットを振り回してるうちに―
I accidentally hit one of them on the head,
たまたま ホームレスの人の頭に
当たっちゃったんです
but it was self-defense!
正当防衛なんですよ
信じてください！
Please believe me!
Mr. Furuta, do you believe him?
古田さん 信じる？
（古田）分からないよ
I don't know.
だが 少なくとも彼は未成年だ
それだけは…
But in either case, he is a minor.
That alone means...
（斉藤）まだ
更生の道もあるかもしれませんね
It might not be too late for him to start over.
今やってることは正当防衛じゃねえ
（古田）だが…
What he's doing right now is NOT self-defense!
But...
（梶浦）
説教は それで終わりか？ ああ？
Are you done preaching? Huh?
She let you have it?
（計）“譲ってもらった”？
Yes. She was a really beautiful woman.
（みか）
うん　とっても きれいな人で…
In the end, I have to use my own strength and...
（みか）最後は自分の力で…
あっ…
バイクのヘルメットに名前…
Oh! There was a name on her bike helmet.
（みか）“S・SAKURAOKA(サクラオカ)”って…
S. Sakuraoka.
Oh...
そっか…
I guess she's out there somewhere,
living her life.
（みか）あの人は
まだ元気に生きてるんだろうな
What am I doing in a place like this?
私 こんな所で何やってんだろう
Anyway, I have to at least get that book back.
でも せめて
あの本は取り戻さなくちゃ
I'll feel kind of bad for her if I don't.
なんだか あのきれいな人に
悪いような気がして
Please stop it, Mr. Kajiura!
やめてくださいよ 梶浦さん…
うるせえ！
てめえの芝居 ムカつくんだよ！
Shut up! Your stupid act is really pissing me off!
You need to turn yourself in to the police.
（古田）警察に自首するべきだ
私が ついていってやってもいい
I don't mind going with you, if you like.
Huh? Who the hell do you think you are?
はぁ？
てめえ 何さまのつもりだよ？
Are you thinking?!
あんたは 一体 何を考えてるんだ？
彼は まだ未成年じゃないか
He's still a minor, but you forced him
to help you kill homeless people?!
それをホームレス殺しの
手伝いをさせたっていうのか？
You know how to use the suit, right?
（計）
スーツの使い方 分かってるな？
What? No, I don't...
（みか）
えっ？ そんなの分からな…
あっ… なに？
What are you doing?
You were using it when Kajiura
was attacking you earlier.
さっき 梶浦に襲われたとき
ちゃんと使ってた
Just wait for me downstairs.
下で待っててくれ
（みか）下って？
"Downstairs"?
I'm going to go get "Labyrinth" back for you.
「迷宮」 取り戻してくる
イヤ… アアーッ！
Put the gun down!
銃を下ろしなさい！ 彼のためにも
もうバカなことは するな！
For his sake and ours, stop being so foolish!
He's right. Please stop it.
そうですよ　やめてください
（梶浦）血管 ぶち切れてきたぜ
You're pushin' it, you know that?!
Nothing pisses me off more
than being preached to!
俺は人に説教されんのが
いちばんムカつくんだよ
What?
Ma'am! What are you doing?
（室戸）先生 何するんですか？
If I have to shoot someone
in order to survive,
（佳乃）どうせ 誰かを殺さないと
生き残れないんなら―
this is better than shooting my own student.
教え子を撃つよりはマシよ
Now put the gun down!
銃を下ろして！
Stop it, everyone!
（古田）
みんな やめろ！ やめるんだ！
Just stop!
これは あの子が持ってた―
This is the book that girl had.
It's called "Labyrinth."
「迷宮」っていう本だ
（計）あっ…
Huh?
There's a great line on the first page.
最初のページに
いいことが書いてある
な… 何を？
（古田）いいから 聞け！
What are you doing?
Just listen!
It says, "No labyrinth is inescapable."
“出られない迷宮はない”って
書いてある
Do you understand?
"No labyrinth is inescapable."
いいか？
“出られない迷宮はない”だ
Give me a break! That's impossible!
冗談じゃありませんよ
そんなはずないでしょう
出られないから
迷宮っていうんですよ
They're called labyrinths because
you can't get out of them!
大の大人が どうして そんなこと
簡単に信じられるんですか？
Why would an adult believe something like that?!
（古田）
信じるのは悪いことじゃない
There's nothing wrong with
believing in something!
It doesn't matter if you're a child or an adult!
大人も子供も関係あるか
（斉藤）
大体 いくら本屋さんでもね
I understand you run a bookstore and all,
今 そんな どうでもいいこと
言っている場合じゃないでしょう
but now's not the time to be going on
over something like this!
No! There MUST be a way out of
this labyrinth! I'm sure of it!
（古田）いや この迷宮を
出られる方法が きっとある
Let's all go home together, alive!
What do you say?
みんなで生きて帰ろうじゃないか
だから銃を下ろせ
Now put the gun down!
I've already pointed a gun at my own student!
私は教え子に銃を向けちゃったのよ
もう帰ったって
まともには生きられないわ
Even if I do get back, how am I
supposed to live with that?!
Don't say that!
（古田）そんなことはない
I don't care about that, Teacher!
Don't say that!
（計）先生 俺 気にしてないから
やけくそになんなよ！
I don't care about that, Teacher!
Come on, please put the gun down!
Don't do anything stupid!
I'm gonna kill you! You know that?!
殺すぞ 殺すぞ！ ああ？
I'm gonna fuckin' kill you!
（梶浦）殺す！ ンンッ…
（計）ハアッ！
Kurono?!
玄野！ ウウッ！
Kurono!
玄野君…
（発射音）
（古田たち）ウワッ！
この人殺し！
You goddamned murderer!
ウワッ…
（梶浦）てめえ！
You son of a bitch!
Kurono!
玄野君！
はじめ！
Hajime!
Shit!
くそ！
Damn it!
Hey, wait!
（古田）おい 待て！ 落ち着け
Calm down!
If you go after him now, it'll just
turn into another all-out brawl.
（古田）やみくもに追っても
また乱戦になるだけだ
They have the woman, so it'll be a while
before they get downstairs.
連中は彼女を連れてるから―
下へ下りるまでには
まだ時間がかかる
In the meantime let's come up with a plan!
その間に作戦を立てよう！
（計）あっ…
C'mon, walk!
（梶浦）ほら 行け！
Why did he try to rescue me?
どうして私なんか助けに来たのよ
Shut up!
（梶浦）うるせえ！
He could've escaped.
逃げられたのに…
I even... I even tried to shoot him!
私 あの子を撃とうとしたのに…
どうして…
Why?
I said shut up! I'll fuckin' rape you, bitch!
うるせえっつうの！ 犯すぞ こら！
Mr. Saito, you've been to this
building before, haven't you?
（古田）斉藤さん あんた このビル
何度か来たことがあるよね
（古田）いやね ほら さっき屋上で
詳しそうなこと言ってたからさ
It's just, when we were on the rooftop earlier,
it sounded as if you knew about this place.
ああ…
まあ ほんの２度ほどですけど―
Well, I've only been here twice... with my boss.
上司のつきあいで…
If we wanted to corner them before they get out
of the building, where would be the best place?
ヤツらがビルから出る前に
追い込むとしたら どこがいい？
That European-style bar on
the first floor, I guess.
（斉藤）え～っと…
１階の洋風の居酒屋かな
Unlike all the adult businesses,
it's got a decent amount of space,
風俗と違って
まあまあスペースあるから―
so it'd give you a better chance of
dodging if they shot at you.
撃たれても よけられるかも
（計）よし 決まりだ
Okay, let's go with that.
１階にヤツらを追い込んでから
先生を取り戻そう
We'll chase them down to the first floor
and corner them, then get Mrs. Yoshino!
They'll just use her as a shield again.
（野崎）また盾にされるぜ
If that happens, I'll try talking to them.
（古田）
そうなったら 私が説得する
そんなの聞く連中じゃないでしょう
They're not the kind of people
who'll sit there and listen!
We'll never be able to get out of here!
It's all over for us!
もう出られっこないですよ
私たちは おしまいだ
In any event, we can't start trying
to kill one another!
とにかく 殺し合いはダメだ
あの子は どうしたんだ？
By the way, what happened to that other girl?
She's outside. She's wearing the suit,
so she should be safe.
（計）外にいる
スーツを着てるから無事なはずだ
No killing, all right?
You can fire only warning shots.
殺し合いは なしだぞ
撃つなら威嚇だけにしてくれ
It's too late for that!
今更 何言ってんだ？
We can get out of here. I'm sure of it.
出られる 必ず！
Impossible!
（斉藤）ムリですってば！
（古田）クッ…
Will you cut it out? Jeez, how can he be so...
あんたは黙っててくれ！
まったく あんたって人は もう…
Kurono.
（野崎）玄野
（計）うん？
Can I ask you a question?
ひとつだけ聞いていいか？
（計）ああ
Yeah.
なんで戻ってきた？
逃げられただろうが
Why did you come back?
You could've escaped.
I kind of liked... the bra
my teacher was wearing.
好きだったんだ 先生のブラ
That's a good one!
そりゃ いいや
（計）フフッ…
Let's just get outside.
とにかく外へ出るぞ
はじめ 撃て！
Shoot it, Hajime!
Who the hell do you think you are,
bossing me around like that?
（室戸）
偉そうに命令してんじゃねえよ
てめえ 帰ったら ぶっ殺してやる
You little shit, I'll fuckin' kill you
when we get back!
Kurono, I'm so sorry...
（佳乃）玄野君 ごめんね
（梶浦）ウッ… 何だ？ てめえ
What are you doing?
We're not going to make it! What do we do?
間に合いませんよ　どうします？
跳び降りろ！ ついでに
スーツの使い方を覚えられる
Just jump! You'll learn how to use your
suit at the same time!
（計）みんな 跳べ！
C'mon guys, jump!
All right!
（古田）よし ンンッ！
（野崎）トリャ！
（斉藤）アア…
I'll shoot... I will shoot!
撃つわよ… 撃つわよ！
Go ahead and shoot. Here, c'mon.
（梶浦）いいぜ 撃てよ
Ah, hell.
Kajiura!
（野崎）梶浦！
（室戸）ウワッ！
（梶浦）おら！ ンンッ…
（計）よし 追い込んだ　行くぞ！
Good, now they're trapped! Let's go!
Hey old man, I'm going to rescue my teacher.
おっさん 先生は俺が助ける
No, it's too dangerous. I'll do it.
ダメだ 私がやる　危険すぎる
I'm experienced at this, so I know how to
use the gun and suit better than anyone.
俺 経験者だから
銃もスーツも いちばん慣れてる
But still...
（古田）いやぁ しかし…
I want you to lead everyone.
（計）あんたはリーダー役 頼む
俺 そういうの苦手だから
I'm just not any good at that kind of stuff.
We used to have a really good
leader but he died...
前は いいリーダーいたんだけど
死んじゃって…
He was great.
すげえヤツだった
みんな まとめて 必死になって
“みんなで帰ろう”って…
He'd pull us all together and say
that we were all going home.
I'm no good at that kind of stuff,
so I'm asking you.
俺 そういうの うまくできないから
あんた 頼むよ
I can't let Gantz do whatever
he wants anymore!
（計）これ以上 ガンツに
いいようにされてたまるか！
You know... you look kind of...
君 前に どこかで…
（計）えっ？
Now you mentioned it...
（野崎）そういえば…
Nah, never mind.
（古田）いや 何でもない
Let's do this.
行くぜ
Teacher!
先生！
You bastards!
てめえ！
What do you care?
いいだろう 別に
どうせ １度死んでんだからよ
She IS already dead after all, right?
I didn't do it! Mr. Kajiura...
Mr. Kajiura...
僕が やったんじゃないですよ
梶浦さんが… 梶浦さんが…
僕は 何も…
So I didn't do... anything...
Hajime!
（梶浦）はじめ！ マジ殺すぞ！
I'll kill you for real! You're the one
who just stabbed this bitch!
今 この女 切り刻んだのは
てめえだろうが！
Stop the bullshit act.
ムカつく芝居だな
What's the boy's problem?
あの子は 一体 何なんだ？
It's called "lust murder".
殺人嗜好症(しこうしょう)ってやつだよ
（古田）まさか…
You've got to be kidding me...
C'mon, old man, don't tell me you're still
going to say he's only a minor or whatever!
おっさん これでも まだ
未成年が どうこう言うのかよ？
アア… もう人質ごっこは やめだ
Geez, I'm through with this taking-hostage crap!
It's just too much work!
面倒くさくて しょうがねえや
Here, she's all yours!
（梶浦）おら 帰すぜ
（計）先生！
Teacher!
Kurono...
（佳乃）玄野君 ごめん…
I'm sorry...
I tried to shoot you earlier.
撃とうとしちゃったよね
（佳乃）あのさ…
I know you used to stare at me during
the class and get aroused...
授業中 先生のこと見て
よく興奮してたでしょう？
なっ… こんなときに なに？
Where did that come from?
I was actually flattered by that.
あれ 結構 うれしかったな
I'm sorry.
（佳乃）ごめんね
（計）あっ…
（梶浦）ウワッ… アアッ！
ハハッ… うれしい！
Simply delightful!
（室戸）アア… 気持ちいい
（梶浦）アアッ…
It feels so good.
PLAY CITY
SHINJUKU
ハァハァ… 逃げたな
He got away...
Are you guys okay?
大丈夫ですか？
What do you think?! Can't you tell by looking?
（野崎）…んなわけねえだろう
見て分かんねえのか？
We'll... protect you... all of us.
あんた 守るよ
みんなで
（みか）えっ？
Am I right, Leader?
（計）そうだろう？ リーダー
（古田）ああ そうだな
Yeah, that's right!
I've already died once.
Nothing can surprise me now.
どうせ １度死んでるんだ
もう何が起きても驚かないよ
（みか）あっ…
（みか）君は…
（計）えっ？
You're...
（みか）あのときの…
You're the guy from back then...
It's too bad she didn't make it,
but she still helped us out.
（古田）亡くなったのは残念だが
あの先生のお手柄だな
Now we can chase them down
using this trail of blood.
この血の痕でヤツらを追える
（みか）あっ… あの…
亡くなったんですか？
You mean... she's dead?!
Oh no...
（みか）そんな…
This is a match between me and Gantz!
ガンツとの勝負だ
I don't know how things will turn out,
何が どうなるか分かんねえけど
あの２人を殺す
but I swear I'm going to kill those two!
It's about time to settle this already!
そろそろ決着つけないとな
No, we have to talk to them first!
（古田）いや 説得が先だ
（計）ンッ… 甘いこと言ってたら
ホントに迷宮から出られなくなる！
You keep up with that soft attitude, and
you'll never make it out of this labyrinth!
I don't care about that yakuza wannabe,
いや あのやくざは ともかく
室戸君は説得して連れて帰る
but I'm going to talk Muroto
into coming back with us.
絶対にだ！
No matter what!
I don't care anymore...
（斉藤）もういいですよ
（みか）斉藤さん…
Mr. Saito?!
私は もうイヤです　行くなら
皆さん 勝手に行ってください！
I'm sick and tired of this!
If you want to go then leave without me!
なにが
“出られない迷宮はない”ですか
To hell with this "there's no labyrinth
without a way out" crap!
I've had enough of it!
ふざけるのも いいかげんにしろ！
You can't stay here! It'll be too
dangerous if we're separated.
（古田）ダメだ 離れると危険だぞ
I'm not going...
私は い… 行かない
無理強いするのは やめろ
and stop trying to force me!
Or I'II... I'll shoot you!
う… 撃つぞー！
It's not a threat! I really will shoot!
脅しじゃない　本当に撃ちますよ
We all start out as pure and innocent babes
Even if you taste the bitter fruit,
don't be discouraged, walk straight
I know it's in the past, but the rain still stings
I'm lonely as floating ice
I kiss your thin finger
And remember you crying
Even if this is the end
I won't forget your last kiss
I won't forget
I won't forget his kiss
I won't lose...
（みか）負けない　死なない
I won't die...
I won't die... Never...
死なない 絶対に
I'll never die!
私は死なない
Next episode, "Let's All Go Back Alive"
次回 “生きて かえろうぜ”